idaho.gov 2013-09-26

# Privacy Policy - Idaho.gov

## Access Idaho Privacy Policy

##### Thanks for visiting the Idaho.gov website.

Our privacy policy is simple: **we collect NO personal information (like names or addresses) when you visit our website**. If you choose to provide that information to us, it is only used to fulfill your request for information or a service.

The State of Idaho is dedicated to protect private information it may collect about its citizens and others from unauthorized access and dissemination in concert with state and federal laws dealing with personal privacy. In order to guarantee a consistent statement of that responsibility, ITRMC has issued this policy.

### Technical Information Collected and How It is Used

We do collect some technical information when you visit in order to make your visit seamless. The following section explains how we handle and collect technical information when you visit our website.

##### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

When you browse, read pages or download information on Idaho.gov, we automatically gather and store specific technical information about your visit. This information (listed below) never identifies who you are. 

  1. The Internet Protocol address and domain name used but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol address to download the pages you request to your computer; 
  2. The type of browser and operating system and the connection speed; 
  3. The date and time you visited this site; 
  4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and 
  5. The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site. 

The information we automatically collect or store is used to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Access Idaho Idaho.gov analyzes web site logs to continually improve the value of the materials available on our sites. Web site logs are not personally identifiable, and we make no attempt to link them with the individuals that browse Idaho.gov.

##### E-mail and Surveys

If, during your visit to Idaho.gov, you participate in a survey or send an e-mail to Idaho.gov, the following additional information will be collected: 

  1. E-mail Correspondence - The e-mail address and contents of the e-mail; and 
  2. Surveys - Any information you volunteered in response to a survey. 

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. The information is retained in accordance with Idaho Open Records Law. 

We use your e-mail address to respond appropriately. This may be to reply to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our web site, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used only for the purpose designated.

### Personal Information and Choice

"Personal information" is information about an individual that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes personal identifiers, such as an individual's name, address, and phone number. Domain names and Internet Protocol addresses are not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an e-mail, applying for some type of license or permit, or participating in a survey). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of Idaho.gov.

If personal information is requested on the web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record, once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult and may be subject to public access.

Children under the age of 13 are not eligible to use services that require submission of personal information and should not submit any personal information to us. This includes submitting personal information to the website as part of a user profile or personalization profile. If you are a child under the age of 13, you can use these services only if used together with your parents or guardians. Seek guidance from your parents or guardians if you are under the age of 13.

If we decide to begin collecting personal information from children under the age of 13, we will notify parents that it is being requested, disclose the reasons for collecting it, and disclose our intended use of it. We will seek verifiable parental consent before collecting any personally identifiable information. If we do collect such information, parents may request information on the type of data being collected, view their child's information, and, if they choose, prohibit us from making further use of their child's information. We will not provide personal information about children to third parties.

### Public Disclosure

In the State of Idaho, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by State government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs: the privacy of individuals is included among these exceptions in both state and federal laws.

We strive to protect personally identifiable information by collecting only information necessary to deliver our services. All information collected at this site becomes a public record that may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption in law exists.

In the event of a conflict between this Idaho.Gov Portal Privacy Notice and the Idaho Open Records Law, or other laws governing the disclosure of records, the Idaho Open Records Law or other applicable laws will control.

### Access Idaho Premium Service and Customer Information for Idaho.gov

Access Idaho will collect, retain and use business/personal information about its customers only when they volunteer to subscribe to an Access Idaho premium service. Business/personal information is only collected, retained, and used by Access Idaho where essential (and allowed by law) to administer its business, and to communicate with and provide products, services and other opportunities to its customers. Access Idaho reserves the right to retain all electronic correspondence (e-mail) and any information contained therein.

Subscriber information will not be sold or rented to any outside company or organization. Access Idaho does not reveal specific information about subscribers or other personally identifiable data to unaffiliated third parties for their independent use, except if required to do so by law.

### Access and Correction of Personal Information

You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe is in error by submitting a written request that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. See Access Idaho Contact Information, section XIII.

### Cookies

In order to better serve you, we use cookies for certain types of online transactions. Cookies are small text files that a web server may ask your web browser to store and to send back to the web server when needed. Cookies may be used to store a transaction identifier or other information a user may provide.

##### Choices about Cookies

The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of many of Idaho's eGovernment services, and we recommend that you set your web browser to accept cookies.

If you have further questions about cookies, the Computer Incident Advisory Capacity Unit that monitors computer problems for the U.S. Department of Energy issued a study on March 12, 1998 of the risks of cookies to users, titled Information Bulletin I-034: Internet Cookies. You can refuse the cookies or delete the cookie file from your computer by using any of the widely available methods.

##### Idaho.gov Practices Regarding Cookies

We do not use cookies to track your visit to our website.

Idaho.gov uses cookies for the following purposes:

  1. When you "sign in" to a State web site, a ?session cookie? is used. For example, if you "sign on" to the Department of Labor section of Idaho.gov as a job seeker, the cookie enables the session to be maintained as you move through different pages, such as updating a multi-page resume or previewing and showing the resume posted. When an employer signs on, the cookies are used to establish the session state. 
  2. The information on these cookies is retained by the State only while the user's session is active in a table that lists unique identifiers. 
  3. Selected applications use ?persistent cookies? to assist users in completing a session. The information on these cookies is retained by the State for a limited period of time and allows the user to continue a session if it is interrupted. An example of this would be a license renewal. If a session is interrupted, the user can return to their session without losing data previously entered. Persistent cookies are used only to assist a user in selected applications and are not used to collect information about the user for other purposes. 

### Security

The Information Technology Resource Management Council (ITRMC) has put policies in place and taken several steps through the Department of Administration (DOA) to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including, but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the entire DOA operating environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice nor as warranting a fail-proof security of information provided through DOA supported web sites.

### Disclaimer

Idaho.gov has links to other websites, including links to web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on Idaho.gov and this Idaho.Gov Portal Privacy Notice will not apply; you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

### Legal Notices

Any trademarks that appear on this site are the property of their respective owners who may or may not be affiliated with, connected to, or sponsored by Idaho.gov. Idaho.gov respects the rights of all copyright holders, and therefore, Idaho.gov has adopted and implemented a policy that provides for the termination in appropriate circumstances of users and account holders who infringe the rights of copyright holders. If you believe that your work has been copied in a way that constitutes copyright infringement, please provide Idaho.gov's Copyright Agent the following information required by the Online Copyright Infringement Liability Limitation Act of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act, 17 U.S.C. 512:

  1. A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed;
  2. Identification of the copyright work claimed to have been infringed, or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site;
  3. Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which is to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit us to locate the material;
  4. Information reasonably sufficient to permit us to contact the complaining party;
  5. A statement that the complaining party has a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; and
  6. A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that the complaining party is authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.

### Contact Information

To offer comments about Idaho.gov or this Portal Privacy Notice, please see ITRMC's [contact information](http://itrmc.idaho.gov/contact.html).

[Full Text of State Policy](http://itrmc.idaho.gov/psg/p1020.pdf) [PDF]
